[{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"1. A set of lithographs published in 1945 depicts eleven of these animals drawn progressively more abstractly. The artist of that work also depicted the head of one of these animals in a sculpture consisting of a bicycle seat and handlebars. Paint was blown onto walls to render these animals in “twisted perspective” at a “Great Hall” in the Lascaux Caves. Kristen Visbal’s sculpture Fearless Girl was installed to face a sculpture of one of these animals on Wall Street. One of these animals can be seen to the left of a horse in Picasso’s Guernica. For 10 points, name these aggressive male cows. ","answer":"ANSWER: bulls [prompt on cows or cattle until mentioned] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"2. This politician’s senior thesis on Saul Alinsky was suppressed at the request of the White House. This cabinet member wrote the article “America’s Pacific Century” to codify the “Pivot to Asia,” and popularized the phrase “women’s rights are human rights” at a speech in Beijing. This politician presented a giant red “reset” button to Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov. She can be seen covering her mouth in Pete Souza’s photo of the Situation Room during the raid on Osama bin Laden’s compound. For 10 points, name this Secretary of State who, as First Lady, supported her husband during the Monica Lewinsky scandal. ","answer":"ANSWER: Hillary Clinton [or Hillary Rodham; prompt on Clinton] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"3. Kobayashi and Maskawa predicted how CP violation for this force necessitates the existence of a third generation of quarks. The gauge bosons for this force, which were discovered by the UA1 and UA2 experiments, are given mass by the Higgs mechanism. Salam, Weinberg, and Glashow were awarded a Nobel Prize for unifying this force with electromagnetism. This fundamental force can cause a down quark to transform into an up quark and an electron antineutrino. This force is mediated by the W+, W-, and Z bosons. For 10 points, name this fundamental force that governs radioactive decay, the second least powerful of the four fundamental forces. ","answer":"ANSWER: weak force [prompt on (radioactive) decay before mentioned] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"4. This figure gives birth to and raises Lava [“LUH-vah”] and Kusha while living in the forest away from her husband. A man draws a circle around this figure to protect her, but she steps out to give alms to an ascetic. This figure undergoes a trial of fire after being reunited with her husband, and gives Hanuman a ring while imprisoned in Lanka. This daughter of King Janaka [“JAW-nuh-kuh”] is said to be born from the earth, and she gets married after a figure strings Shiva’s bow at her swayamvara [“swaw-YUM-vuh-ruh”]. This figure’s desire for a golden deer leads her husband to leave her in the forest. For 10 points, name this wife of Rama who is abducted by Ravana in the Ramayana. ","answer":"ANSWER: Sita [“SHEE-tah”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"5. This character reveals his dislike of capital punishment while describing a guillotining he witnessed in France to a house servant. He exclaims “a man's faith might be ruined by looking at that picture!” upon viewing a copy of Hans Holbein’s Body of the Dead Christ in the Tomb. While delivering a speech on aristocracy at a dinner party, this character accidentally destroys a prized Chinese vase. This character, who harbors romantic feelings for Aglaya and Natassya, is eventually sent back to a Swiss sanitorium to seek treatment for his epilepsy. For 10 points, name this simple-minded title character of a Fyodor Dostoyevsky novel. ","answer":"ANSWER: Prince Lev Nikolayevich Myshkin [or the Idiot] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"6. The ratio of two isotopes of this element in ice cores is used as a paleothermometer to determine prehistoric temperatures. One molecule that contains this element appeared about 2.45 billion years ago in a namesake “great event” that was correlated with the emergence of cyanobacteria. This element can become depleted in lakes through the process of eutrophication. This element, which is found along with silica in all feldspars, is the most abundant element in the Earth’s crust. An allotrope of this element is removed by CFCs in a layer of the stratosphere. For 10 points, name this element found in ozone. ","answer":"ANSWER: oxygen [or O] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"7. Linguistic syncretism is the phenomenon in which one of these units performs multiple grammatical functions, such as the word “bet” being both a past and present tense form. The “zero” form of this unit does not have any phonetic realisation, as in the plural of “sheep.” The ratio of these things to words determines whether a language is more analytic or synthetic. Agglutinative languages express grammatical functions by stringing a large number of these units together. These units are “bound” if they cannot stand alone, such as the affix “un-.” Unlike phonemes, they possess a meaning. For 10 points, name these smallest grammatical units of language. ","answer":"ANSWER: morphemes "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"8. A woman in this collection is surprised to receive a sword in place of flowers, causing her to exclaim “No more doll’s decorations for me!” At the end of this collection, the speaker compares his life reaching “its eternal Home” to “a flock of homesick cranes.” The speaker of this collection describes himself as a “frail vessel” that has been “emptiest again and again.” This collection begins by telling God “thou hast made me endless, such is thy Pleasure.” The introduction to this collection was written by William Butler Yeats. For 10 points, name this collection of “Song Offerings” by Bengali poet Rabindranath Tagore. ","answer":"ANSWER: Gitanjali [or Song Of erings before mentioned] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"9. A siege of this city was aided by Imre Thököly and his army of Kuruc [“koo-ROOTZ”] rebels. Nicholas of Salm commanded the defense of this city atop walls that were partially financed by the ransom of Richard the Lionheart. Cannons captured during a siege of this city were later cast into bells for St. Stephen’s Cathedral. Eugene of Savoy entered the service of this city’s ruler during a failed siege led by Kara Mustafa Pasha. This city was rescued from that 1683 siege by the cavalry of Polish King Jan Sobieski. For 10 points, name this city that twice withstood Ottoman sieges, the capital of Austria. ","answer":"ANSWER: Vienna [or Wien] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"1. Another composer from this country featured 840 repetitions of a theme in his Vexations, and wrote a set of three piano pieces named for a dance performed by naked Spartan boys. A group of experimental composers from this country known as “The Six” were influenced by a man from this country who composed the Gymnopédies. For 10 points, name this home country of Arthur Honegger and Erik Satie. ","answer":"ANSWER: France [or French Republic] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"1. Debye’s law predicts that a solid’s specific heat is proportional to the third power of this quantity. The root-mean-squared speed of a gas represented by the Maxwell–Boltzmann distribution is proportional to the square root of the ideal gas constant times this quantity, over the molar mass. Thermodynamic beta is defined as one over the product of Boltzmann’s constant and this quantity. The zeroth law of thermodynamics considers two systems with the same value of this quantity as a third system. The smallest possible value of this quantity is absolute zero. For 10 points, name this quantity that measures the average kinetic energy of a system, whose SI unit is the Kelvin. ","answer":"ANSWER: temperature [prompt on T] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"2. This religion’s orthodox sect was founded by a follower of Mason Remey, who is considered a “covenant breaker” under this religion’s Lesser Covenant. This religion’s short obligatory prayer ends by calling God “the Help in Peril, the Self-Subsisting.” This religion’s governing body issues an annual worldwide message during this religion’s twelve-day festival of Riḍván, which commemorates a speech its founder gave in a garden. This religion’s central text is the Kitáb-i-Aqdas. A Ten Year Crusade by this religion’s first Guardian, Shoghi Effendi, ended with the creation of this religion’s Universal House of Justice. For 10 points, name this religion founded by Bahá'u'lláh. ","answer":"ANSWER: Bahá'í Faith [or Baha'iyyah] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"3. This crop was brought to Chikmagalur, India by the Sufi saint Baba Budan. The dying indigo industry was replaced with this crop by the oligarchy of the Fourteen Families in El Salvador. Fazendas producing this crop dominated the São Paulo economy during a period named for “[this crop] with milk” in Brazil. With his mule Conchita, Juan Valdez is an iconic representative of this crop in Colombia, where it is grown in a namesake triangle. Cultivation of this crop in Java began after the Dutch obtained some plants from the Yemeni port of Mocha. For 10 points, name this crop whose arabica beans are used to make cappuccinos. ","answer":"ANSWER: coffee "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"4. At the 2018 FIFA World Cup, this national soccer team used the basketball-inspired “love train” strategy of attacking corner kicks. Members of this team were photographed frolicking on inflatable unicorn pool toys a day after they defeated Tunisia on a last-minute header. The coach of this team became a surprise fashion icon after online sales of his trademark navy waistcoat skyrocketed. The phrase “it’s coming home” became a meme after this team defeated Colombia and Sweden to reach the World Cup semi-finals, where they lost to Croatia. For 10 points, name this Gareth Southgate-coached national soccer team that plays home matches at Wembley Stadium. ","answer":"ANSWER: England national soccer team [prompt on The Three Lions; do not accept or prompt on “United Kingdom” or “Great Britain”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"5. Eighteen of these objects symbolize eighteen stories in a 1951 collection partially named for some possessed by a Wisconsin carnival worker. Sarah Ruth believes one of these objects is sacrilegious in Flannery O’Connor’s story “Parker’s Back.” Alvaro drops a condom while discussing one of these objects with Serafina in a Tennessee Williams play titled for a Rose one of them. According to Ishmael, these “purplish yellow” objects can result from a white man falling among cannibals; Ishmael makes this observation after seeing that Queequeg’s body is covered in these objects. For 10 points, name these artworks that cover the body of Ray Bradbury’s Illustrated Man. ","answer":"ANSWER: tattoos [accept illustrations before “Sarah Ruth” is read, prompt afterwards; accept specific descriptions of tattoos like The Rose Tattoo and tattoos of Jesus] 16.This philosopher quoted another man’s “first principles of demonstration” in a passage that states that “no one can mentally admit the opposite of what is self-evident.” A text by this philosopher takes an argument from “the governance of the world.” That text by this philosopher borrows from another thinker by defining “motion” as reducing something from potentiality to actuality, and includes sets of objections followed by contradicting statements introduced with the Latin phrase “sed contra.” This philosopher argued that God is the first efficient cause in his five proofs for God’s existence. For 10 points, name this author of the Summa Theologica. "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"7. This musician improvised a jazz break to open his solo during a 1946 recording of “A Night in Tunisia” with Miles Davis. Charles Mingus’ Mingus Revisited was originally released under the title Pre-[this musician’s name]. After pawning his instrument for heroin, this musician used a Grafton plastic instrument to perform in a famous quintet at Massey Hall. This musician reworked a theme from Ray Noble’s “Cherokee” for his composition “Ko-Ko.” He quoted “How High the Moon” in a song that references his nickname, “Ornithology.” For 10 points, name this bebop saxophonist who was nicknamed “Bird.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Charlie “Bird” Parker Jr. [prompt on Yardbird or Bird] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"8. At the end of one of this author’s novels, the title character watches a goose jump over the head of his lover Marmaduke Bonthrop Shelmerdine. In another novel by this author, the title character decides to “buy the flowers herself,” and is compared to a lily by her former lovers Peter Walsh and Sally Seton. This lover of Vita Sackville-West wrote a satirical “biography” of an Elizabethan genderfluid poet, Orlando. In her best-known novel, World War I veteran Septimus Smith jumps out a window as the title character, Clarissa, prepares to throw a party in London. For 10 points, name this author of Mrs. Dalloway. ","answer":"ANSWER: Virginia Woolf "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"9. This process is controlled by the bZIP [“BEE-zip”] class of proteins, which contain leucine zipper motifs and include the protein MafK [“MAFF-KAY”]. It can be terminated prematurely by attenuators, which are an example of cis-regulatory elements. David Hogness and Michael Goldberg identified a sequence critical to the initiation of this process called the TATA [“TAH-TAH”] box. “Factors” that control the rate of this process may bind to activators or promoters. After this process occurs, introns are removed during the process of splicing. For 10 points, name this process in which an mRNA strand is created from DNA, and which occurs before translation. ","answer":"ANSWER: transcription [accept transcription factors] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"0. An ivory statuette of the goddess Lakshmi discovered at this non-Asian location is thought to have come from northern India. A monarch who visited this site was so alarmed by its erotic artwork that he had it confined to a Secret Museum. Giuseppe Fiorelli developed the process of making plaster casts of corpses at this site. Frescoes depicting the initiation rites of a mystery cult were unearthed in this site’s Villa of Mysteries, and a mosaic of Alexander the Great was displayed in this site’s House of the Faun. Pliny the Elder died trying to rescue victims near this place at Herculaneum. For 10 points, name this Roman town that was destroyed by the eruption of Mount Vesuvius. ","answer":"ANSWER: Pompeii Tiebreaker. This taxonomic class includes the family Reduviidae, which has earned the nickname “assassin” due to their nature as ambush predators. Another animal in this class native to the Americas produces carminic acid, from which the dye carmine is made. Animals in this class include the cochineal and an organism that stays underground during a 13- or 17-year long life cycle. Hemiptera is an order in this class, whose members may enter the imago stage after emerging from the pupa. For 10 points, name this class that includes aphids and cicadas. "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name this city. Two neighbors discover that their spouses are having an affair with one another in In the Mood for Love, a 2000 film set in this city that introduced its Second Wave of filmmakers to global audiences. ","answer":"ANSWER: Hong Kong "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Hong Kong cinema initially gained international fame through films in this genre, exemplified by the work of Wong Fei-hung and the Shaw Brothers. Later, it was popularized by actors like Bruce Lee and Jackie Chan. ","answer":"ANSWER: martial arts films [or kung fu films or karate films; prompt on action films] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] The director of In the Mood for Love, Wong Kar-wai, often collaborates with Christopher Doyle, who has this profession. This member of a film crew controls the film’s lighting, lensing, and overall visual aesthetic. ","answer":"ANSWER: cinematographer [or director of photography; or DP; or DOP] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] This Oxford scholar used the word “hwæt” so much his students thought it meant “quiet.” He argued that scholars should appreciate Beowulf as a literary work, not a historical one, in “The Monsters and the Critics.” ","answer":"ANSWER: J.R.R. Tolkien [or John Ronald Reuel Tolkien] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] This Irish poet translated “hwæt” as a casual “so” in his “New Verse Translation” of Beowulf. His collection Death of a Naturalist includes a poem about an “old man” who “could handle a spade,” “Digging.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Seamus Heaney "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] C.K. Scott Moncrieff, who translated “hwæt” as “what” in his version of Beowulf, is better known for his English translations of literature in this language, including books by Proust and The Song of Roland. ","answer":"ANSWER: French "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Wife-carrying races are inexplicably popular in this Scandinavian country, which hosts many Nordic walking races in and around its capital city of Helsinki. ","answer":"ANSWER: Republic of Finland [or Suomi] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"5. ","answer":"ANSWER: Iditarod Trail Sled Race "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Christopher McDougall's Born to Run brought attention to the Tarahumara people of this country, who are renowned for their abilities to run long distance races barefoot. The rodeo-like sport of charreada was invented in this country. ","answer":"ANSWER: Mexico 4.This country experienced the Killing Time after rebels issued the Sanquhar Declaration in response to a monarch’s renunciation of the Treaty of Breda. For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name this country where Covenanters led by the Earl of Argyll fought off the imposition of episcopacy. ","answer":"ANSWER: Scotland [prompt on United Kingdom or Great Britain] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] While king of Scotland, this monarch attempted to integrate the Church of Scotland with Anglican episcopacy in his Five Articles of Perth. This first Stuart king of England also authorized an English translation of the Bible. ","answer":"ANSWER: James I of England [or James VI of Scotland] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] This theologian ushered in the Scottish Reformation by writing the Scots Confession. He attacked female rulers in his pamphlet The First Blast of the Trumpet Against the Monstrous Regiment of Women. ","answer":"ANSWER: John Knox "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name this conic section, which consists of points that are equidistant to a single point called the focus and a line called the directrix. ","answer":"ANSWER: parabola "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Simpson’s rule is a method of performing this task using parabolas. The trapezoidal rule is another technique for doing this task. ","answer":"ANSWER: numerical integration [or approximating a (definite) integral; or approximating the area under a curve; prompt on area] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] This function of x generates a catenary in the xy-plane. It equals the average of the functions “e to the x” and “e to the negative x.” ","answer":"ANSWER: hyperbolic cosine of x [or cosh of x] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] In an essay, Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie claimed that “we should all be” these people. Roxane Gay considers herself a “bad” one of these people because she likes rap music and the color pink. ","answer":"ANSWER: feminists "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Essayist Jill Lepore wrote about this historical figure’s sister Jane in her Book of Ages. In Ann Petry’s novel The Street, Lutie Johnson follows the ideals presented in this man’s essay “The Way to Wealth.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Benjamin Franklin "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] In The Empathy Exams, Leslie Jamison describes performing this job for medical students. Jennifer Lawrence asked why she made less in this profession than her male counterparts in a piece for Lena Dunham’s newsletter. ","answer":"ANSWER: acting [or being an actor or actress] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name this modern-day country where an 1830 performance of The Mute Girl of Portici inspired this country’s Walloon and Flemish ethnic groups to secede from the United Provinces. ","answer":"ANSWER: Belgium "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] The Mute Girl of Portici was a patriotic work of this type. Italian nationalists supported unification under King Victor Emmanuel II with their slogan “Viva Verdi,” which referenced the name of a composer of these works. ","answer":"ANSWER: operas "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] This French diplomat’s plan to partition Belgium and annex Wallonia was rejected at the London Conference. This notoriously duplicitous minister represented France at the Congress of Vienna. ","answer":"ANSWER: Charles Maurice de Talleyrand-Périgord "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name this American scientist. He also formulated a phase rule that gives the number of degrees of freedom of certain multi-component systems. ","answer":"ANSWER: Josiah (Willard) Gibbs "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Gibbs also names a type of “free energy” which is equal to this quantity minus the product of entropy and temperature. This quantity, equal to the internal energy plus PV, is symbolized H. ","answer":"ANSWER: enthalpy "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Enthalpy is considered one of these types of functions. These types of functions do not depend on the path between two positions of a system. ","answer":"ANSWER: state functions "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name this process that comes in contagious, hierarchical, and stimulus varieties. In the study of geography, this term refers to the spread of a phenomenon. ","answer":"ANSWER: diffusion "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Leo Frobenius coined a form of diffusion involving this concept. Carl Sauer founded a branch of geography focusing on this concept, which encompasses the beliefs, customs, and values of a people. ","answer":"ANSWER: culture [or cultural diffusion; or cultural geography] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] This 1997 book partially examines the role of diffusion in explaining why Eurasian civilizations became the dominant world powers, a process largely aided by the title entities. ","answer":"ANSWER: Guns, Germs, and Steel: The Fates of Human Societies (by Jared Diamond) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name these creatures from Greek myth who attempted to abduct Hippodamia on her wedding day, thus inciting a war with the Lapiths. The bodies of these creatures are half-man, half-horse. ","answer":"ANSWER: centaurs "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] This wise centaur didn’t join his more rowdy brethren in their attempted abduction of Hippodamia. He tutored Jason and Achilles. ","answer":"ANSWER: Chiron "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] The centaurs were produced by this Lapith king’s union with the cloud nymph Nephele. Hermes punished this king by strapping him to a fiery wheel, which spins in Hades for all eternity. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ixion "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name this Romantic era pianist who popularized performing from memory. This composer of the Soirées musicales and a piano trio in G minor is depicted in the 11th section of another composer’s Carnaval. ","answer":"ANSWER: Clara Schumann [or Clara Wieck; prompt on Schumann] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Clara Schumann and Joseph Joachim were both musicians from this country, as was Clara’s husband Robert Schumann. ","answer":"ANSWER: Federal Republic of Germany [or Bundesrepublik Deutschland] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Clara premiered this close friend’s piece Variations and Fugue on a Theme by Handel. Clara also premiered this composer’s Opus 49, which contains a famous “lullaby” dedicated to this composer’s friend Bertha Faber. ","answer":"ANSWER: Johannes Brahms "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"8. ","answer":"ANSWER: organesson [or Or] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Organesson is the heaviest-known element in this group on the periodic table. Elements in this group, whose lightest element is helium, are relatively unreactive due to their completely filled valence shells. ","answer":"ANSWER: noble gases [or inert gases; or Group 18] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] This noble gas element is produced in stars from the fusion of oxygen and helium, making it the fifth most abundant element in the universe by mass. This gas is commonly used in gas-discharge tubes for lighting. ","answer":"ANSWER: neon [or Ne] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name this type of place. These places are often the setting of works by Native American writers, such as Louise Erdrich's Love Medicine. ","answer":"ANSWER: Native American reservations "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"8. ","answer":"ANSWER: Sherman Alexie "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] The contemporary Mojave poet of When my Brother was an Aztec has this last name. Another author of this surname wrote This is How You Lose Her and a novel about an overweight Dominican nerd. ","answer":"ANSWER: Diaz [accept Natalie Diaz; accept Junot Diaz] (the novel alluded to in the second sentence is The Brief Wondrous Life of Oscar Wao) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name these two concepts, which one philosopher argued were a priori notions that grounded all comprehension of sense experience. That philosopher structured human experience using cause and effect and these two concepts. ","answer":"ANSWER: space and time [accept in either order] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] This philosopher argued that space and time were integral to the structure of human experience. This man wrote Groundwork of the Metaphysics of Morals and defined categorical imperatives in another of his works. ","answer":"ANSWER: Immanuel Kant "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] This Kant text argues for transcendental idealism of space and time and discusses the analytic-synthetic dichotomy. This text is the first in a series of three Kant texts including ones about “Practical Reason” and “Judgment.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Critique of Pure Reason "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"1. ","answer":"ANSWER: Democratic Republic of the Congo [or Congo-Kinshasa; or Congo-Léopoldville; do not accept or prompt on “Zaire”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] This motorcycle-riding revolutionary arrived in the Congo to instruct the Simbas in his foco theory of guerilla warfare. This Argentine-born comrade of Fidel Castro is immortalized in the Guerrillero Heroico photograph, ","answer":"ANSWER: Ernesto “Che” Guevara [prompt on El Che] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Che Guevara initially joined up with a Congolese rebel with this surname, but broke off on his own because that rebel was too lazy. Another former guerilla with this surname is the D.R. Congo’s current president. ","answer":"ANSWER: Kabila [Laurent-Désiré Kabila or Joseph Kabila] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name this filtration system possessed by animals in Mysticeti, a subgroup of Cetacea. ","answer":"ANSWER: baleen [accept whalebone] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] The baleen system is used by this heaviest living species of whale, which is widely believed to be the largest animal that has ever existed. ","answer":"ANSWER: blue whale [or Balaenoptera musculus] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Blue whales belong to this family of baleen whales that also includes the fin and minke whales. Lunge feeding in this family is believed to be the largest biomechanical event on Earth. ","answer":"ANSWER: rorquals [or Balaenopteridae] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name this character who mentions “the public works of Puncher and Wattmann” in the aforementioned monologue, which he delivers after another character commands him to “Think!” ","answer":"ANSWER: Lucky "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Lucky appears in a play titled for this character. Because this character never actually appears during the play, some critics argue that he symbolizes God. ","answer":"ANSWER: Godot [or Waiting for Godot] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] This Irish playwright, who wrote Waiting for Godot, rejected that analysis, claiming, “If by Godot I had meant God I would have said God, and not Godot.” He also wrote Endgame and Happy Days. ","answer":"ANSWER: Samuel Beckett "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name this syncretic Caribbean religion that worships orishas like Olodumare. The Supreme Court case Lukumi Babalu v. City of Hialeah concerned this religion’s practice of animal sacrifice. ","answer":"ANSWER: Santería [or Regla de Ocha] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] This other syncretic Caribbean religion originates from Haiti. Namesake dolls, zombies, and other witchcraftrelated practices are commonly associated with this religion, which worships spirits called loas. ","answer":"ANSWER: Vodou [or Voodoo] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Elekes, things that consist of these objects, are received in the first stage of the Santería initiation process. Practitioners of Islam use misbahas, which consist of these objects, during dhikr. ","answer":"ANSWER: beads [or prayer beads] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name this Swiss Neoclassical painter best known for her history paintings, such as Cornelia Presenting Her Children as Her Treasures. ","answer":"ANSWER: Angelica Kauffmann "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Kaufmann was one of two women who helped found this English institution, led initially by Joshua Reynolds. Because the two weren’t allowed in its 1772 group portrait, Johann Zoffany included portraits of them on this institution’s wall. ","answer":"ANSWER: Royal Academy of Arts "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] The other female founder, Mary Moser, gained prominence through her paintings of these plants. Many critics have emphasized the sexual nature of Georgia O’Keefe’s paintings of these plants. ","answer":"ANSWER: flowers [accept more specific answers] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name this city infiltrated by the Culper Ring during its occupation by William Howe’s British forces. This city’s Great Fire of 1776 may have been set by arsonists loyal to the American cause. ","answer":"ANSWER: New York City "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] After the British spy John André was captured, Tallmadge acted to stop him from being sent to this American general at West Point, whom Tallmadge correctly suspected of being a traitor. ","answer":"ANSWER: Benedict Arnold "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Tallmadge was a Yale classmate of this other spy who was captured in New York City. Before being hanged, this spy exclaimed “I only regret that I have but one life to lose for my country.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Nathan Hale Tiebreaker. The Annals of one of this empire’s rulers are inscribed in the British Museum’s Taylor Prism. For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name this empire whose ruler Sennacherib razed Babylon to the ground. Sennacherib ruled from this empire’s capital city of Nineveh. ","answer":"ANSWER: Assyrian Empire "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Sennacherib’s Annals mentions his unsuccessful 701 BCE siege of this city, which was ruled by King Hezekiah. The Tanakh records that Hezekiah stripped the gold from this city’s Temple of Solomon to pay tribute to Sennacherib. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jerusalem "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] This ruler sacked Jerusalem and destroyed its Temple in 597 BCE, ushering in the Babylonian Captivity. According to Josephus, this king built the Hanging Gardens of Babylon. ","answer":"ANSWER: Nebuchadnezzar II [prompt on partial answers]"}]
